<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>event-sourcing on Jacy Gao</title><link>http://jgao.io/tags/event-sourcing/</link><description>Recent content in event-sourcing on Jacy Gao</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 15:13:17 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jgao.io/tags/event-sourcing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consistency Patterns of Distributed Transaction</title><link>http://jgao.io/post/patterns_of_distributed_transation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 15:13:17 +1100</pubDate><guid>http://jgao.io/post/patterns_of_distributed_transation/</guid><description>A distributed transaction is a set of operations on data that is performed across two or more data repositories. Consider 2 UPDATE SQL operations need to be performed across 2 separate databases where both operations need to be either successful or failed. In this case, SQL Transaction which is supported on a single node is no longer sufficient.
Two-Phase Commit Protocol (2PC) In such transaction processing across multiple nodes, a Two-Phase Commit Protocol is sometimes implemented to coordinate all participated processes in a distributed transaction on whether to commit or abort and roll back the transaction.</description></item><item><title>Common Pitfalls of Event Sourcing</title><link>http://jgao.io/post/event-sourcing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 23:20:45 +1000</pubDate><guid>http://jgao.io/post/event-sourcing/</guid><description>Event Sourcing defines a different way to represent state of the data in a domain. Instead of maintaining the latest state of a single domain object in the database (CRUD), Event Sourcing promotes storing a full history of event logs which can be played sequentially to construct the current or past state of a domain object.
I started working with Event Sourcing over 5 years ago. Many lessons were learned along the journey.</description></item></channel></rss>